# Carlos Daniel Jiménez M.

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST · MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER · STATISTICAL ENGINEER

Colombia

🛮 (+57) 322-816-9956 | 🗷 danieljimenez88m@gmail.com | 🏕 www.danieljimemezm.com | 🖸 carlosjimenez88M | 🛅 djimenezm

## **Summary** \_

Experienced Senior Data Scientist with a demonstrated history of working in the Startups and public institutions between USA, Colombia, Chile and México. With more than ten years of experience applying and development Machine Learning models to real world.

Appasionate for applied statistics, machine learning modeling and bayesian statistics and skilled in: Applied Machine Learning, Statistical Modeling, NLP, Deep Learning, Bayesian Data Analysis, Marketing Analytics, Bio-statistics (Genomic Data analysis), LaTeX and Markdown.

You can find my Portfolio clicking here

## Work Experience\_

Globant

Machine Learning Engineer Oct 2020 - Currently

- Developer various Machine Learning models for task like: Computational vision, Forecasting, Speech Recognition, NLP and Classification
- Data Science product development for globant's clients
- · Mentor for Jr Data Scientist.

### **Inter-American Development Bank**

USA

PRINCIPAL DATA SCIENTIST CONSULTANT

Jul 2020 - Currently

- Developing Machine Learning applications to understand the public policies of the different governments
- Deep Learning developer for NLP products
- Developer various Machine Learning models for tasks like text classification and forecast labor in LatinAmerica

#### **Resolve Studio - Chiper**

Col

CHIEF DATA SCIENCE AND DATA ENGINEERING

Jan 2019- May 2020

- Lead Data Scientist and Machine Learning developer for autonomous attributions campaings with Deep Learnning and another technologies
- Developed Data Science models solutions for classification and Data Analysis
- · Lead Data Science Team for automate solutions and tasks throughout the company such as client sales prediction, demand forecast

Big Bang Data

PRE SALES ENGINEER AND DATA SCIENTIST

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2019

- lead sales of products based on data and machine learning
- · Developed Machine Learning models for: Marketing, Pricing, forecast, and Churn with differents clients
- · Evaluated and Creator of work methodology

#### Secretaria de Educación Distrital

Co

Data Scientist Aug 2017 - Aug 2018

- Data Scientist on an advanced analytics team working in education projects and innovations in big data tools (RStudio and Hadoop)
- Build and own complex data pipelines using SQL and other data processing tools
- I Created sampling model for Evaluated Educational Progress

## Superintendencia de Puertos y Transporte

Col

STATITICIAN AND QUANTITATIVE ANALYST

2017

- Created BI and tools that identify opportunities and some risk for projects
- · Worked with other departments to use new technologies to streamline Goverment policies and rules
- Developed a Mac and Windows python application for Policies evaluation software to measure employee productivity.

## **Puedo ser Consulting Group**

Col

CHIEF STATISTICS

Jan 2017 - Sep 2017

March 2014 - Apr 2015

- I developed of Statistics Models to: Clusters, Marketing Analytics and Forecast
- I created Statistics department

## New Port Negocios Internacionales New Port International Business

Col

• Researched on strategies to optimize pickup planning in warehouses

- Researched on strategies to optimize pickup planning in warehou
   Support Data Science initiatives across the company
- Research the applications of AI in Marketing

JANUARY 24, 2021 DANIEL JIMÉNEZ · RÉSUMÉ

Invershop SAS Col

Marketing' Chief

Marc 2012- March 2014

- Researched on technologies to create scalable multi-tenant software Marketing
- Developing of intelligent reporting for supporting the Marketing management team
- Creation and development of Machine Learning algorithms for Marketing Strategies

#### ONU - Secretaria de Desarrollo Económico 'La Pintana'

Chile

ASSOCIATE ECONOMIST 2012

- · I Researched and analyze labor market conditions, national and MSA patterns, and past and future market trends and forecasts
- I created Psychology Test for Social development
- I Worked with media to customize Growth Destiny's data and insights for their stories/inquiries

## Academic Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Col

Professor

Dic 2019 - Currently

- Manager and creator program's on Data Science and Big Data
- Visiting professor at health school:Evaluation of medical alternatives
- Last courses(click on the course 'name to see the content)
  - Anomaly Detection in Python
  - Git and Github
  - Digital Data Science
  - Big Data
  - Machine Learning (Introduction)
  - Bayesian Data Analysis

Uniempresarial Col

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR March 2018 - Occasionally

- Courses Creator on Data Sciene, BI, Computational Science and Econometrics for Business
- · Academic Consultat on Metacognition
- Teacher subjects on university levels :Big Data, Computational Science, Statistics and Data Analysis

Educación Futuro Col

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR May 2015- Apr 2016

- · Teacher at the chair of Statistics and KPI's
- Courses Creator on law of the unemployed : Innovation Diploma and Business Computing

UniAsturias México

ECONOMICS PROFESSOR 2015

• Full professor in following subjects: Microeconomics, Political Theory, Asian Economics, Economics History and Mathematical Economics

## Education

Santo Tomás University

Bogotá - Col

M.S. IN STATISTICS

Jan 2018 - Currently

• focus in: Bayesian Statistics, EDA and Machine Learning Applied

Santo Tomás University

Bogotá - Col

Focus in : Maths for Economics

Jan 2010 - Dec 2014

Focus in : Matris for Economics

## Tools

B.A IN FCONOMICS

Programming: Python: +4, R: +9, Octave:+3, Matlab:+2

**Data Science:** Tidymodels,keras,Tenserflow,Scikit Learn, tidyverse,Spark,Bigquery,MySQL,Tidymetrics

**Development:** Docker, Git, Google Cloud Platform, Plumber, Flask.

Visualization: Shiny, looker, Power BI, Shiny metrics, Google Analytics

## **Areas of Interest**

Applied Machine Learning, Natural Lenguage Processing, Statistical modelling, Econometrics (with Big Data), Inferential Statistics, Genomic Data Analysis, Meta - Analysis, Bayesian data analysis, Web Scrapping, Forecasting and Deep Learning.

## Publications \_\_\_\_\_

## Inferencia estadística un enfoque moderno

www.danieljimenezm.com

FREE

2020

• Design of the theoretical framework of the application of statistical inference applied to data science

## **Extracurricular Activity**

danieljiemezm.com Colombia

BLOGGER Aug 2018 - currently

Blog on Applied Statistics, Data Analysis and Machine Learning with R

Nostradamusdata.com Col-Chile

TEACHER Jun-2019- currently

Special Professor on Data Science and BI

## **Speaking Engagements & Conferences**

## El motor del emprendimiento a través de UX con Ciencia de Datos

Bucaramanga - Colombia

GOOGLE FOR STARTUPS

2020

Lecturer

Machine Learning aplicado al mundo de la publicidad

Bogotá - Colombia

2020

Principal Lecturer

**Interpretability Machine Learning (Labor Economics Models)** 

Washington - USA

INTER-AMERICAN DEVELOPMENT BANK

2020

Lecturer

**Data Science and Educations** 

Bogotá-Colombia

CTB 2018

Lecturer

ONU

**Economics History: Democracy Under Threat** 

Bogotá- Colombia

Universidad Santo Tomás

2017

Principal Lecturer

**Crime Economics in Latam: Religion and Patterns** 

Santiago de Chile - Chile

2015

Principal Lecturer